

ENCRYPTO, Department of Computer Science of Technical University of Darmstadt, Germany

"Be weird. Be random. Be who you are. Because you never know who would love the person you hide."

# Research Interests

My research focuses on cryptography and information security, emphasising efficient and secure protocols for problems in the area of Multi-party Computation (MPC). My current focus is on MPC for privacy-preserving services on the internet and in the area of Machine Learning and Federated Learning. The topics of cryptography I have been interested in so far include MPC, Verifiable Secret Sharing, Oblivious Transfer, Byzantine Agreement and Broadcast, Privacy-Preserving Machine Learning and Federated Learning.

# Education

#### Indian Institute of Science (IISc)

PH. D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2017 - Jul. 2021

- · Dissertation Area: Secure Multi-party Computation (MPC) & Privacy-Preserving Machine Learning (PPML)
- Dissertation Title: MPCLeague: Robust MPC Platform for Privacy-Preserving Machine Learning
- · Advisor: Prof. Arpita Patra
- CGPA: 9 / 10 (First Class with Distinction)

#### Indian Institute of Science (IISc)

M.Tech. (Research) in Computer Science

Aug. 2014 - Jun. 2017

- Dissertation Area: Secure Multi-party Computation (MPC)
- Dissertation Title: Fast Actively Secure OT Extension for Short Secrets
- Advisor: Prof. Arpita Patra
- CGPA: 6.83 / 8 (First Class with Distinction)

#### College of Engineering, Trivandrum (CET)

B.TECH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

- Thesis Title: Proximity-based Sentiment Analysis with Contextual Phrase Polarity
- CGPA: 8.81 / 10 (First Class with Distinction)

#### Trivandrum, India

Bengaluru, India

Bengaluru, India

Jul. 2010 - Apr. 2014

# **Professional Experience**

#### Technical University (TU) of Darmstadt

POST-DOCTORAL RESEARCH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Darmstadt, Germany

- Oct. 2021 Mar. 2023 Area: Privacy-preserving Services On the Internet (PSOTI)
- · Host: Prof. Thomas Schneider
- Research Group: Cryptography and Privacy Engineering (ENCRYPTO)

#### **Indian Institute of Science (IISc)**

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

RESEARCH INTERN

Bengaluru, India

Darmstadt, Germany

Nov. 2019

Aug. 2021 - Sep. 2021

· Research associate under the guidance of Arpita Patra.

# **Technical University (TU) of Darmstadt**

• Research work under the joint guidance of Thomas Schneider and Arpita Patra.

• The project aimed at improving the efficiency of secure two-party computation.

• Resulted in a publication at USENIX Security Symposium'21.

### **Amazon Development Centre**

Bangalore, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER (SDE) INTERN

Jul. 2013 - Aug. 2013

· Worked on the project titled "Increase the registered and subscribed user base at Amazon" under the mentorship of Bhanu Pratap Singh in the International Expansion (Junglee Traffic) Team.

# Awards, Scholarships and Achievements

- 1. Nominated for the Schmidt Science Fellows 2022 program for post-doctoral research (one among a group of 350 highly accomplished candidates, nominated from 83 of the world's leading universities and institutes).
- 2. Represented country India in the "Window to the World" session at the 8th Heidelberg Laureate Forum.
- 3. Selected as one among 225 young researchers to participate in the 8th Heidelberg Laureate Forum.
- 4. Recipient of Google PhD Fellowship 2019 (one among 53 researchers around the globe).
- 5. Organiser of Secure Multi-Party Computation: Theory and Practice Workshop at Indian Institute of Science (IISc) from 19th to 22nd January, 2020.
- 6. Received travel grant to attend Privacy Preserving Machine Learning Workshop, CCS 2019, London.
- 7. Received travel grant to attend Workshop: Theory and Practice of Secure Multiparty Computation 2016, Aarhus University, Denmark.
- 8. Secured All India Rank of 807 with a score of 688 in GATE 2014 among (approximately) 1,55,190 students in India.
- 9. Ministry of Human Resource and Development (MHRD) Scholarship for Postgraduate education, India.
- 10. Best Outgoing student in Computer Science and Engineering (P Rathnaswamy Memorial Endowment) for the year 2014.
- 11. First prize in Coding Competition, CODESTORM, conducted by IEEE Computer Society (March 2013).
- 12. Received Ashok Leyland "ALL THE BEST" Scholarship for graduate studies, India (February 2011).
- 13. Recipient of Federal Bank Hormis Memorial Foundation Scholarship for graduate studies, India (2010-11).
- 14. Recipient of Indian Oil Education Scholarship for graduate education, India (2010-11).
- 15. Received Central Sector Scholarship by Department of Higher Education (MHRD) for graduate studies, India (2010).
- 16. Achieved a rank of 629 in Kerala Engineering Entrance (KEAM 2010) among (approximately) 100949 students.
- 17. Received Malayala Manorama Merit Scholarship (February 2008).
- 18. Received prize at CMS Math Prodigy Hunt 2009, organized by Centre for Research in Mathematics.
- 19. Participated in 20th Kerala Science Congress, Trivandrum (January 2008).
- 20. Participated in Youth Parliament Competition under the auspices of the Institute of Parliamentary Affairs, Government of Kerala.

# **Skills**

**Programming** C/C++, Java, Javascript, Python, PyTorch

DevOps AWS, DockerDBMS Oracle, SQL

**Web** HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, JSP **Tools** NetBeans, Eclipse, ŁTFX

### Personal Data\_

**Born** 24th April 1992 in Kerala, India

**Citizenship** Indian **Marital Status** Married

**Languages** Malayalam (mother tongue), English, Hindi, Tamil

**Interests** Photography, Badminton, Cycling